mercurymagazines.com 2019-08-13

# Privacy

M2 Business Media, LLC values your privacy and is dedicated to protecting your personal information. Our privacy statement is a summary of our privacy policy. 

M2 Business Media may log IP addresses (a unique number assigned to every computer on the Internet) in order to improve security, analyze trends and administer our offers. We track your movement within the site, the pages from which you were referred, access times and browser types. We take measures to protect all the personal information you provide at all times. You may remove yourself from our customer database at any time, as described in our Privacy Policy. You also have the opportunity to correct or change certain information you have provided to us. 

M2 Business Media is committed to provide you with: 

## Notice 

  * What personally identifiable information we collect 
  * How the information is used 
  * With whom the information may be shared 

## Consent 

What choices you have regarding collection, use and distribution of the information 

## Security 

Procedures we use to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of the information 

## Access 

How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information we have collected from you 

Last Updated: 12/3/2018

This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices for M2 Business Media, LLC. ("we" "us" or "our"). 

## A Special Note About Children 

Persons under the age of 18 are not eligible for any offers presented by M2 Business Media. Our site is not intended for or directed to children under the age of 13. If you are aware of an instance in which a child under the age of 13 has provided personal information to us, please let us know (through the below contact information), so that we may promptly delete such information or take other appropriate action. 

## Registration 

We request information from you on our subscription and order forms. This registration information is used by us for order fulfillment, customer service and to understand your areas of interest. We act as an agent to collect data for some of our partners that deliver products or services that consumers order. For example, when ordering a subscription, users are required to provide certain personal data such as name, title, company, address, telephone, email and various industry questions specific to the demographic interests. This information is then provided to our partner or their agent for fulfillment. 

## Tracking Technology 

If you have been offered our services through one of our marketing partners or affiliates (see "Use of Information" section below), we may share the information you enter with that partner or affiliate. To do so, we may use a technology called clear GIFs, which automatically transfers the information you enter. 

## Log Files 

We log IP addresses (a unique number assigned to every computer on the Internet) in order to improve security, analyze trends and administer our offers. We may track your movement within the site, the pages from which you were referred, access times and browser types. 

We (or a third party platform we work with) also may place cookies (discussed below) on your web browser, and assign a unique identifier (a "UID") to those cookies. These UIDs may be used, for instance, to customize content or marketing to you.

## Cookies

Our site, like most other Web sites, uses cookies when you visit our site. Cookies are small bits of data that remain on your computer hard drive that allow us to make your visit to our site more enjoyable and provide you with a more personalized experience. Cookies are used for various purposes, such as remembering information that you have already entered, for instance your password and preferences, so that you will not have to re-enter them every time you visit and keeping information previously provided for certain services available on the site. They also tell us general information about how users visit our site, such as which pages they've visited and what services they use, so we can further customize the information we provide. This will make our site more valuable to you, since the information provided will be tailored to your tastes. However, please note that despite such setting, our site does not respond to such requests and will continue to use cookies for tracking purposes even if you have set your browser to not allow them. You can also manually delete all cookie files from your computer whenever you choose. We use cookies only for your convenience and to enhance your visit to our site. You can view Google's uses of information here: <https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites>.

We may also use (or work with third party platforms that use) cookies for ad targeting purposes - such as to target ads to you (often through the use of a UID) when you are on one of our websites or another website. If you wish to opt out of these cookies, please go to the Section titled **"Interest-Based Advertising and Your Marketing and Advertising Choices"**

#### Combination of Information

We may combine any of the information that we collect about you, such as your registration information and a UID. Sometimes, the third parties we work with will also combine information they collect about you - for instance, by connecting a UID they have used to identify your browser to information about your browser activity on other web pages. (To opt out of this information being used for ad targeting purposes, please see the below section titled **"Interest-Based Advertising and Your Marketing and Advertising Choices"** below). We refer to all of the information that we describe and collect in this Privacy Policy as your "information."

## Use of Information 

We use the information we collect from you in the following ways:

  * ### Contractual Relationships 

We provide the information you provided or that we've collected to, and make it available to, our third party service vendors with whom we have contractual relationships for the purpose of servicing our processing of your magazine subscriptions. These vendors provide various services on our behalf such as customer service, tech support, marketing support, data enhancement, security support and web hosting. 
  * ### Publishers 

When you request a magazine, we forward your contact and address information (and sometimes, other information we've collected from or about you) to the applicable magazine publisher to determine your eligibility for fulfillment. The magazine publishers for the titles you have chosen to receive may use the information you provided to present you with other opportunities in accordance with their own privacy policies. When requesting a magazine, we encourage you to read the privacy statement of the publisher for that magazine; we do not enforce (or write) the privacy policies of the publishers in our program and are not responsible for their actions. 
  * ### Retailers/Special Offers 

When you choose to accept a special offer, we forward your contact information (and sometimes, other information we have collected from you) to the applicable retailer and/or sponsor for fulfillment. The retailers and/or sponsors for the offers you have chosen to receive may use the information you provided to present you with other opportunities in accordance with their own privacy policies.  
  * ### Third Party Marketing Affiliates 

If you accept one of our offers by linking through one of our partners or affiliates, your information also may be shared with the partner or affiliate which originated the link to our site. These partners and affiliates may use the information you provided (and/or that we collected) to present you with other opportunities in accordance with their own privacy policies. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of our partners and affiliates. 
  * ### Exceptional Circumstances

Please note that if M2 Business Media or any of their lines of business is sold or disposed of as a going concern, whether by merger, sale of assets or otherwise, the relevant customer database of M2 Business Media could, in whole or in part, be sold as part of that transaction. We also may have to release personally identifying information when it is necessary to comply with judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants or orders.   We also use (and share) information for interest-based advertising purposes, as more fully described below. 

## Interest-Based Advertising and Your Marketing and Advertising Choices

_a. Interest Based Advertising_. We work with third party platforms to help serve advertising, which may be through display, email, direct mail, or other methods. These third party platforms use technologies like cookies and GIFs that we describe above. These platforms may use these technologies to (i) inform, optimize, and serve ads based on past visits to our services and other sites (or other information about you), (ii) serve ads on other sites, (iii) report how our advertising performs (for instance, whether advertising impressions may be related to visits to our Site other transactions or activities), or (iv) analyze website visits or ad campaigns in other ways. This type of advertising - i.e., using activity collected over time and across sites to serve more relevant ads - is often called "interest based advertising." 

Similarly, when we work with these ad platforms, we or they may place cookies (or similar technologies) that have been associated with de-identified (such as through "hashing" de-identification formulas) demographic or other data linked to or derived from data you voluntarily have submitted to us (e.g., your email address) and that we may share with a service provider to trigger or suppress an ad. Through these and other identifiers (which are de-identified but may have been derived from your contact information), service providers we work with may target, measure, or analyze advertising to you on a variety of other platforms (for our products or other products), such as through direct mail, email, or "connected" television channels, as well as social media platforms.

_b. Your Choices: Opting Out of Interest-Based Advertising_. If you are interested in more information about tailored browser advertising and how you can generally control cookies from being put on your computer or mobile browser to deliver interest-based advertising, you may visit the Network Advertising Initiative's Consumer Opt-Out Link and/or the Digital Advertising Alliance's Consumer Opt-Out Link and on those sites, you may opt-out of receiving tailored advertising from companies that help serve those ads. Opting out in this way won't prevent you from receiving ads - it will only (in many cases) make those ads less relevant, because they won't be tailored to your interests. Also note that the above opt-outs are cookie-based, so if you delete your cookies (or change your browser), you'll need to opt out again. We do not control any of the above opt-out links and are not responsible for any choices you make using these mechanisms or the continued availability or accuracy of these mechanisms. 

Further, we may work with data providers who collect web log data from you (including IP address and information about your browser or operating system), or place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive interest-based ads or content through web, mobile or other media channels. The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, that we may share with a data provider solely in hashed, non-human readable form. To opt-out of these data provider cookies, please visit http://www.aboutads.info/choices or http://www.networkadvertising/choices.

## Links 

Subscription offers may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that M2 Business Media is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by M2 Business Media. 

## Security 

M2 Business Media takes measures to protect the personal information you enter by using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption, which is recognized as an industry standard in encryption technology, whenever you enter personal information. There may be several publication qualification forms that are linked directly on our partner's site. Although we strongly encourage our partners to employ similar security measures, we cannot and will not be responsible for the privacy practices of these other parties and their sites. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this site.

## Special Offers and Choice/Opt-Out 

After you complete our subscription forms, your answers and contact information are sent to the publisher of the magazines you requested so they can determine your eligibility and fulfill your subscriptions. These publishers may also contact you with special offers. From time to time, we may present you with specially selected offers from M2 Business Media or one of our partners. Out of respect for your privacy, you can forfeit any of these opportunities by [clicking here](http://m2mediagroup.mkt5930.com/preferences/MercuryMagazinesM2RewardsOptOut) to remove yourself from receiving future offers.

## Site and Service Updates 

We communicate with you to provide requested services and on issues relating to your subscriptions. We also send site and subscription service updates. You are not able to unsubscribe from these important announcements, which contain important information about your subscriptions and M2 Business Media. 

## Correcting/Updating Personal Information 

If you want to change any personal information you previously provided to us (such as your address) you can do so by emailing us at: [service@mercury-magazines.com ](mailto:service@mercury-magazines.com). 

## Notification of Changes 

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. The most current version of the policy will govern our use of your information and will be available at <https://rewardsurvey.com/Home/PrivacyPolicy>. If we make a change to this policy by continuing to access or use this site after those changes become effective, you agree to be bound by the revised Privacy Policy.

## Information Collection and Use 

M2 Business Media is the owner of the information collected on this site. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact the M2 Business Media Privacy Department by emailing us at: [privacy@mercury-magazines.com ](mailto:privacy@mercury-magazines.com)
